<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="CVS - Merging from one branch to another">

	<intro 
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-cheatsheets.htm">
		<description>
This cheat sheet will automatically launch wizards, perform actions, and guide you through the individual steps to merge changes from a CVS branch into another branch, or into HEAD. To learn more about using cheat sheets or to see a list of available cheat sheets click help (?).To start working on this cheat sheet, click the "Click to begin" button below.
		</description>
	</intro>

	<item
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-100b.htm"
		title="Determine Branch and Version Information">
		<description>
In this step you must determine the name of the branch or version that contains your changes and the version from which the branch was created. This is a manual task, you will need to perform the work and click the "Click to complete" button to move to the next step. 
		</description>
	</item>

	<item
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-100b.htm"
		title="Load the Destination into your Workspace">
		<description>
Select the project and choose Replace With &gt; Another Branch or Version from the context menu. Then select the branch to replace with. In this step you must ensure that the destination is loaded into your workspace. This is a manual task, you will need to perform the work and click the "Click to complete" button to move to the next step.
		</description>
	</item>

	<item
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-100b.htm" 
		title="Merge Details">
		<description>
Select the project, choose Team &gt; Merge and complete the wizard as required. This step specifies the details of the merge.  This is a manual task, you will need to perform the work and click the "Click to complete" button to move to the next step.
		</description>
	</item>

	<item
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-100b.htm"
		title="Work with the Merge Editor">
		<description>
In the Merge editor manually merge the changes. This step loads the required changes into the workspace. This is a manual task, you will need to perform the work and click the "Click to complete" button to move to the next step.
		</description>
	</item>

	<item
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-100b.htm"
		title="Commit your changes">
		<description>
Select Team &gt; Synchronize with Repository and then commit all the changes to the repository. This step finalizes the transfer of the changes from the workspace to the CVS repository. This is a manual task, you will need to perform the work and click the "Click to complete" button to move to the next step.
		</description>
	</item>

</cheatsheet>