<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS TYPE="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>
<contexts>

	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Wizard Pages 						-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="share_project_page_context">
      <description>This page helps you select what type of target site you wish to connect the project to.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="import_project_set_page_context">
      <description>This page helps you import a project set from a file on the filesystem. A project set is a lightweight description of a set of shared projects. It can be used to reconstruct a lineup of shared projects that you have in your workspace.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="export_project_set_page_context">
      <description>This page helps you export a project set to a file which can be shared with other team members. A project set is a lightweight description of a set of shared projects. It can be used to reconstruct a lineup of shared projects that you have in your workspace.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="target_new_site_page_context">
      <description>This page helps you select a site to which your project should be connected. You may choose from the list of existing sites, or create a new site.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="target_mapping_selection_page_context">
      <description>This page helps you choose the folder on the seected site where your project should be connected. You may choose an existing folder, or create a new folder.</description>
   	</context>
	
	
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Preference Pages 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="ignore_preference_page_context" >
      <description>You may wish to exclude certain resources from version control. Resources whose names match any enabled pattern will not be released. The wildcard characters '*' and '?' are permitted. These settings will not affect resources already under version control.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TargetMenuActions 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context id="target_get_action_context">
   		<description>Downloads the selected resources from the site into your workspace.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="target_put_action_context">
   		<description>Uploads the selected resources from your workspace to the site.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="target_synchronize_action_context">
   		<description>Show any differences between the local and remote site state of the selected resources in the Synchronize view.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="target_getas_action_context">
   		<description>Downloads the selected resources from the site into your workspace. You may specify the local name of the resources.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="target_getasproject_action_context">
   		<description>Downloads the selected resources from the site into your workspace. A project is created in the workspace for each of the selected items.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="target_disconnect_action_context">
   		<description>Discards the selected target sites from the list of remembered sites.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TargetCatchupReleaseViewer			-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context id="target_catchup_release_viewer_context">
   		<description>This view shows incoming, outgoing and conflicting changes.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TargetActions						-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
   	
   	<context id="sync_get_action_context">
   		<description>Downloads the selected resources from the site into your workspace.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="sync_put_action_context">
   		<description>Uploads the selected resources from your workspace to the site.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Views					            -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="site_explorer_view_context">
      <description>The Site Explorer view allows you to browse of the contents of known target sites and download remote resources into the local workspace.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- SiteExplorerViewActions		    -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="add_site_action_context">
      <description>Creates a new target site to which you can upload or download resources.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="new_folder_action_context">
      <description>Creates a new folder on the target site.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- SyncViewActions				    -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="refresh_action_context">
      <description>Refreshes the contents of the view.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="expandall_action_context">
      <description>Fully expands all selected items.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context  id="remove_action_context">
      <description>Removes the selected items from the Synchronize view.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context  id="navigator_show_action_context">
      <description>Selects and reveals the selected items in the Navigator view.</description>
   	</context>
 
</contexts>