<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS TYPE="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>
<contexts>
   <context  id="new_cvs_connection_action_context" >
      <description>example</description>
	<topic label="Repositories - Concept" href="concepts/concepts-27c.htm"/>
 	<topic label="Repositories - Reference" href="reference/ref-47.htm"/> 
   	<topic label="CVS Repositories" href="reference/ref-47.htm"/>
	<topic label="Create a Repository Location" href="tasks/tasks-92.htm"/>
   	<topic label="Disconnecting from a Repository" href="tasks/tasks-94.htm"/>
   </context>
   
	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TagSelectionDialog 				-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context id="replace_tag_selection_dialog_context">
   		<description>You have chosen to replace the selected resources with a branch or version tag. This dialog allows you to select the tag which is to be used for this operation. The selected resources will be replaced with those tagged with the selected tag. If the desired tag does not appear in the list of Versions or Branches, perform a "Refresh from Repository" or a "Configure Tags" to automatically or manually find the tags that exist in the repository. Disabling the "recurse into sub-folders" option will restrict the operation to selected folders and their direct children and selected files only.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="compare_tag_selection_dialog_context">
   		<description>You have chosen to compare the selected resources with a branch or version tag. This dialog allows you to select the tag which is to be used for this operation. The selected resources will be compared with those tagged with the selected tag. If the desired tag does not appear in the list of Versions or Branches, perform a "Refresh from Repository" or a "Configure Tags" to automatically or manually find the tags that exist in the repository.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="tag_remote_with_existing_dialog_context">
   		<description>You have chosen to tag the selected resources with an existing branch or version tag. This dialog allows the user to select the tag which is to be used for this operation. If the tag already exists on another revision of any of the selected resources, it will be moved to the revision in the selection. If the desired tag does not appear in the list of Versions or Branches, perform a "Refresh from Repository" or a "Configure Tags" to automatically or manually find the tags that exist in the repository. Disabling the "recurse into sub-folders" option will restrict the operation to selected folders and their direct children and selected files only.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="share_with_existing_tag_selection_dialog_context">
   		<description>The project being shared already exists remotely. This dialog allows the user to select the branch with which the project is to be shared. If the desired tag is not HEAD and does not appear in the list of Branches, perform a "Refresh from Repository" or a "Configure Tags" to automatically or manually find the tags that exist in the repository.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TagAsVersionDialog 				-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="tag_as_version_dialog_context">
   		<description>Enter the version name to be used to tag to the selected resources.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- WizardPages 						-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="sharing_autoconnect_page_context">
   		<description>The local project has CVS information assocated with it but is not registered as a CVS project. This page shows the CVS information associated with the local project. Clicking "Finish" will register this project as a CVS project and enable the use of CVS menu commands. If "Validate Connection on Finish" is enabled, a connection will be attempted to the server.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="sharing_select_repository_page_context">
   		<description>Either choose the repository to share the project with from the list of existing repositories or indicate that a new repository location is to be created.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="sharing_new_repository_page_context">
   		<description>Enter the information that identifies the repository you would like to share with and the user and connection information required to access this repository.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="sharing_module_page_context">
   		<description>Specify the name of the remote module with which the local project is shared. You can either choose to use the project name as the name that will be given to the remote module or to specify a custom module path. In either case, the name is relative to the repository root directory and, if the remote module does not exist, it is created.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="sharing_finish_page_context">
   		<description>The sharing wizard has all the information it needs to share the project with the repository. Click "Finish" to share the project.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="patch_selection_page_context">
   		<description>Specify where you would like the patch output saved.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="patch_options_page_context">
   		<description>Specify various options used to generate the patch.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="keyword_substituton_selection_page_context">
   		<description>Select the mode to be applied to the selected files. Automatic will choose between Binary and the default ASCII mode specified in the CVS preferences depending on a file's type as determined using the Team file type registry.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="keyword_substituton_summary_page_context">
   		<description>The files whose mode requires a change based on the wizard input are listed. Optionally, those whose mode do not require changes can be included in the list. This mode associated with a file in the list can be modified by clicking on the file's mode and selecting from the list.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="keyword_substituton_shared_page_context">
   		<description>Select whether files that are already shared with the repository are to be considered for change. If include shared files is disabled, only new files that have already been added to CVS control will be considered.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="keyword_substituton_changed_page_context">
   		<description>Select whether files that contain outgoing changes are to be considered for mode change.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TeamMenuActions 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context id="team_synchronize_action_context">
   		<description>Shows any differences between the local and remote state of the selected resources in the Synchronize view.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="team_synchronize_outgoing_action_context">
   		<description>Shows any differences between the local and remote state of any selected resources that have outgoing changes in the Synchronize View.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_commit_action_context">
   		<description>Commits any outgoing changes in the selected resources to the server.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_update_action_context">
   		<description>Updates the selected resources with any remote changes.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_create_patch_action_context">
   		<description>Creates a patch that, when applied to the same base as the local resources, will duplicate the selected resources.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_tag_as_version_action_context">
   		<description>Tags the selected resources in the repository with a version name provided by the user.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_branch_action_context">
   		<description>Creates a branch using the selected resources as the base and optionally updates the local resources to be on the new branch.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_merge_action_context">
   		<description>Merges the changes from one branch into another.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_set_keyword_mode_action_context">
   		<description>Sets the keyword substitution mode of the selected resources.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_disconnect_action_context">
   		<description>Disconnects the project from CVS control and optionally deletes the CVS folders.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_add_action_context">
   		<description>Adds the selected resources to CVS control so they can be committed and shared.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_ignore_action_context">
   		<description>Ignores the selected resources so that they will not be considered during any CVS operations.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="team_nature_to_property_action_context">
   		<description>Converts a project that has a CVS nature on it to one that has a persitant property. This is only required for migration from pre-F3 to post-F3 workspaces.</description>
   	</context>
   		
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Other Menu Actions 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context id="compare_with_tag_action_context">
   		<description>Compares the selected resources with the corresponding remote resources tagged with a user specified version or branch tag.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="compare_with_latest_action_context">
   		<description>Compares the selected resources with the corresponding remote resources with the same tag or on the same branch.</description>
   	</context>

   	<context id="compare_with_revision_action_context">
   		<description>Compares the selected file with a user specified revision of the file.</description>
   	</context>
   	
 	<context id="replace_with_tag_action_context">
   		<description>Replaces the selected resources with the corresponding remote resources tagged with a user specified version or branch tag.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	 <context id="replace_with_latest_action_context">
   		<description>Replaces the selected resources with the corresponding remote resources with the same tag or on the same branch.</description>
   	</context>
    
   	<context id="replace_with_revision_action_context">
   		<description>Replaces the selected file with a user specified revision of the file.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="checkout_as_action_context">
   		<description>Checks out the selected resource into a user configured project.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="checkout_as_project_action_context">
   		<description>Checks out the selected resources into projects that corresponds to the name of each remote resource.</description>
   	</context>

   	<context id="checkout_module_action_context">
   		<description>Checks out the selected modules into the local workspace.</description>
   	</context>
   	   	
   	<context id="open_remote_file_action_context">
   		<description>Opens the contents of the selected remote file in an editor.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="show_in_history_action_context">
   		<description>Displays the revision history of the selected local or remote file in the history view.</description>
   	</context>

 	<context id="compare_remote_resources_action_context">
   		<description>Compares the two selected remote resources with each other.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="copy_repository_name_action_context">
   		<description>Copies the name of the selected repository location to the clipboard.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="remove_root_action_context">
   		<description>Removes the selected repository locations from the Repositories View.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="define_branch_action_context">
   		<description>Adds a branch to the selected repository location. This operation only adds the branch to the view and does not affect the repository itself.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="remove_branch_action_context">
   		<description>Removes a branch from the selected repository location. This operation only removes the branch to the view and does not affect the repository itself.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="move_remote_tag_action_context">
   		<description>Tags the selected resources with an existing user specified tag, moving the tag if required.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="tag_remote_action_context">
   		<description>Tags the selected resources with a user specified tag.</description>
   	</context>
   	   	  	
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- TagConfiguration 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
	
	<context  id="tag_configuration_overview" >
   		<description>Configure the branch and version tags that are shown in the workbench. By browsing remote CVS files for tags you can selectively choose, from the list of tags on each file, which tags should be remembered and which should not. You can also select the files that will be automatically examined for tags.</description>
   	</context>
   
    <context  id="tag_configuration_refreshlist" >
      <description>This lists the files that are automatically examined for tags. By default, the .project file	is examined. But in some cases other files may have a more complete tag history and should be examined instead.</description>
   	</context>
   
   	<context  id="tag_configuration_refreshaction" >
      <description>This will fetch branch and version tags from the files that have been configured to be automatically searched for tags. If tags that you expected to see do not appear, try changing the list of files to examined via the tag configuration dialog.</description>
   	</context>

 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Dialogs					        -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context id="release_comment_dialog_context">
       <description>Enter a comment to describe the contents of this release.</description>
    <!-- Below copied from old VCM
       <topic label="%context_ref_vcm_releasing" href="tasks/tasks-114.htm" />
    -->
    </context>
   	<context id="user_validation_dialog_context">
      <description>In this dialog, enter the appropriate information to log in to the repository.</description> 
    <!-- Below copied from old VCM
      <topic label="%context_ref_vcm_repositories_concept" href="concepts/concepts-27c.htm" /> 
      <topic label="%context_ref_vcm_create_repository_location" href="tasks/tasks-92.htm" /> 
      <topic label="%context_ref_vcm_repositories_reference" href="reference/ref-47.htm" />
    -->
    </context>
    <context id="tag_local_as_version_dialog_context">
      <description>Enter the name of the version tag to be applied to the revisions that exist locally.</description>
    </context>
    <context id="branch_dialog_context">
      <description>Enter the name of the branch tag to be applied to the revisions that exist locally.</description>
    </context>
    <context id="add_to_cvsignore_context">
    	<description>In this dialog choose how to add the selected resources to the .cvsignore files. For each resource to be ignored, a .cvsignore file will created in its parent directory containing the pattern specified in the dialog. This will not affect resources already under version control.</description>
    </context>
    
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Preference Pages 					-->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context  id="prune_empty_directories_pref" >
      <description>Enables pruning of empty directories on update and in the synchronization view. Although pruned directories aren't shown in the workbench there is actually still an empty directory in the repository.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context  id="quietness_level_pref" >
      <description>Sets the amount of status information CVS prints for a command. In "Somewhat quiet" mode the printing of unimportant informational messages is supressed. The consideration of what is important depends on each command. In "Very quiet" mode all output except what is absolutely necessary to complete the command is suppressed. In "Very Quiet" mode, some CVS servers may not communicate important information about errors that have occured. You may want to consider using "Somewhat quiet" mode instead.</description>
   	</context>
   	
  	<context  id="compression_level_pref" >
      <description>Sets the compression level on communications with the server if it is supported by the server. Level 1 is minimal compression (very fast/low compression) and level 9 maximum compression (very slow/maximum compression).</description>
   	</context>

	<context  id="default_keywordmode_pref" >
      <description>Sets the default keyword substitution mode to use for ASCII files.</description>
   	</context>
   	
	<context  id="comms_timeout_pref" >
      <description>Sets the amount of time in seconds to wait before timing out from a connection to the CVS server.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context  id="consider_content_pref" >
      <description>Sets the default compare method for comparing and synchronizing CVS resources. By default timestamps are used to compare CVS files, and this is by far the fastest method. However, in some cases a more accurate comparison can be achieved by comparing file content. This setting can be toggled from within a compare editor or the synchronization view.</description>
   	</context>

	<context  id="markers_enabled_pref" >
      <description>Enables markers to be added to the task view for resources that have been locally removed but not committed and resources that have been locally added but not placed under CVS control.</description>
   	</context>
   	
	<context  id="replace_deletion_of_unmanaged_pref" >
      <description>Allows resources not under CVS control to be deleted when replacing with resources from the repository.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Views					            -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context  id="console_view_context" >
      <description>This view shows the output of CVS operations.</description>
   	</context>
   	<context  id="repositories_view_context" >
      <description>This view allows the browsing of the contents of known CVS repositories and the checkout of modules into the local workspace as projects.</description>
   	</context>
   	<context  id="resource_history_view_context" >
      <description>This view shows the revision history of a file under CVS control.</description>
   	</context>
   	<context  id="catchup_release_viewer_context" >
      <description>This view shows the incoming, outgoing and conflicting changes.</description>
   	</context>
   	<context  id="compare_revisions_view_context" >
      <description>This view allows the comparision of the local copy of a file with the revisions from the respoitory. Actions available for a revision are "Get Contents" and "Get Revision". Although both replace the local file with the contents of the remote rvision, "Get Revision" will make the local file "sticky". This means that changes to the file cannot be committed back to the repository.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Actions					        -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
 	<context  id="get_file_revision_action_context" >
      <description>Loads the revision of the file into the workspace. The file will be "sticky" and the user will be unable to commit changes to the repository.</description>
   	</context>
 	<context  id="get_file_contents_action_context" >
      <description>Loads the contents of the file into the workspace. The base revision of the local file will not change and the file will become dirty. Perform this action if you wich to revert to the contents of an older revision of the file.</description>
   	</context>
   		
   	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	<!-- Sync Actions					    -->
 	<!-- ********************************** -->
 	
   	<context id="sync_commit_action_context" >
      <description>Commits the selected outgoing changes to the CVS repository. Conflicting changes are not committed; to commit them you must use the "Override and Commit" action.</description>
   	</context>
   	
   	<context id="sync_forced_commit_action_context">
      <description>Commits the selected conflicting and incoming changes to the CVS repository. Non-conflicting outgoing changes are not committed; to commit them you must use the "Commit" action.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="sync_update_action_context">
      <description>Gets the selected incoming changes from the CVS repository. Conflicting changes are not updated; to update them you must use the "Override and Update" action.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="sync_forced_update_action_context">
      <description>Gets the selected conflicting and outgoing changes from the CVS repository. Non-conflicting incoming changes are not updated; to update them you must use the "Update" action. If some of the selected resources are auto-mergeable (i.e. they have no line-based conflicts) then you have the option of either performing an auto-merge or replacing with the remote content.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="sync_add_action_context">
      <description>Adds the selected resources to CVS control.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="sync_ignore_action_context">
      <description>Adds the selected resources to the appropriate .cvsignore file. These resources will no longer be considered for repository operations.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="merge_update_action_context">
      <description>Gets the selected incoming changes from the CVS repository. Conflicting changes are not updated; to update them you must use the "Override and Update" action.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="merge_forced_update_action_context">
      <description>Gets the selected conflicting changes from the CVS repository. Non-conflicting incoming changes are not updated; to update them you must use the "Update" action. If some of the selected resources are auto-mergeable (i.e. they have no line-based conflicts) then you have the option of either performing an auto-merge or replacing with the remote content.</description>
   	</context>
	
	<context id="merge_update_with_joinaction_context">
      <description>Gets the selected conflicting changes from the CVS repository. Non-conflicting incoming changes are not updated; to update them you must use the "Update" action. When performing a merge, it is difficult to detect if conflicts are auto-mergeable (i.e. they have no line-based conflicts). If you believe the file is auto-mergeable, you may use this action. You will then have the option of either performing an auto-merge or replacing with the remote content.</description>
   	</context>
	
</contexts>
