<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<form>
   <p><b>Generated content</b></p><p>This plug-in has been created using content templates. The following templates were used:</p>
   <li style="text" value="1."><b>XML Editor.</b>This template creates a basic XML editor.  It has all the basic functions of an editor, such as cut, copy, paste, find, etc.  It also has syntax highlighting and supports double-clicking.</li>
   <li style="text" value="2."><b>"Hello world" Action Set.</b>This template creates a simple action set that adds <b>Sample Menu</b> to the menu bar and a button to the tool bar. Both the menu item in the new menu and the button invoke the same <b>Sample Action</b>. Its role is to open a simple message dialog with a message of your choice.</li>
   <li style="text" value="3."><b>Help Table of Contents.</b>This template creates a Help table of contents. If this table is set to primary, it can be standalone, or integrated into pre-set categories. If the table is not set to primary, it can optionally be integrated into a primary table of contents for testing. </li>
   <li style="text" value="4."><b>Multi-page Editor.</b>This template creates a multi-page editor. It works on text files with the chosen extension. The editor has three pages: <b>Edit</b> where you enter text, <b>Properties</b> that allows you to change font of the result and <b>Preview</b> that shows sorted words from the <b>Edit</b> page using the font set in <b>Properties</b>. To open the editor, choose <b>File</b>, <b>New</b> then <b>Other...</b> from the menu bar. In the "Simple" category, choose to create a new file. Use any file name, but use the extension the editor is registered for (*.mpe by default).</li>
   <li style="text" value="5."><b>New File Wizard.</b>This template creates a wizard that can create a new file in the workspace. It is designed to generate files that can be opened by a <b>Multi-Page Editor</b>. To test the wizard, select <b>File</b>, <b>New</b> then <b>Other...</b> from the menu bar. When the master wizard opens, select the created category and the new wizard registered for that category. Make sure that the chosen extension matches the extension the multi-page editor is registered for (*.mpe by default).</li>
   <li style="text" value="6."><b>Perspective Extensions.</b>This template creates extensions to the target perspective.  It adds a view shortcut, a wizard shortcut, a perspective shortcut, an action set and a view to the target perspective.</li>
   <li style="text" value="7."><b>Popup Menu.</b>This template adds a submenu and a new action to a target object's popup menu.  This contribution will appear in all viewers where an object of the specified type is selected.</li>
   <li style="text" value="8."><b>Preference Page.</b>This template creates a page that is contributed to the Preferences. It demonstrates how to create common preference fields and how to save and restore values between invocations. To see the result, select <b>Window</b> then <b>Preferences...</b> from the menu bar.</li>
   <li style="text" value="9."><b>Property Page.</b>This template adds a property page to a resource and will appear in the Properties Dialog for that resource.  This property page can be used to view and set application-specific properties of a resource.</li>
   <li style="text" value="10."><b>View.</b>This template creates a workbench view. The view is contributed to the workbench by creating a category. The view can be opened by selecting <b>Window</b>, <b>Show View</b> and then <b>Other...</b> on the menu bar. The template offers several choices including pop-up menu support, local tool bar, double-click, sorting and filtering.</li>
   <p/><p><b>Tips on working with this plug-in project</b></p><li>For the view of the new plug-in at a glance, go to the <img href="test"/><a href="OverviewPage">Overview</a>.</li><li>You can test the contributions of this plug-in by launching another instance of the workbench. On the <b>Run</b> menu, click <b>Run As</b> and choose <img href="test"/><a href="action.run">Run-time Workbench</a> from the available choices.</li><li>You can add more functionality to this plug-in by adding extensions using the <a href="action.newExtension">New Extension Wizard</a>.</li><li>The plug-in project contains Java code that you can debug. Place breakpoints in Java classes. On the <b>Run</b> menu, select <b>Debug As</b> and choose <img href="test"/><a href="action.debug">Run-time Workbench</a> from the available choices.</li>
</form>

