<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<welcomePage 
	title="Eclipse Platform"
	format="nowrap">
	<intro>This page will help familiarize you with the Eclipse Workbench.
To get started, read the sections below and click on the related links. </intro>

<item><b>Installed Features </b>
To find out more about the features installed in your workbench, choose <action pluginId="org.eclipse.ui"  class="org.eclipse.ui.internal.QuickStartAction">Help > Welcome...</action>
and select the feature you are interested in.</item>

<item><b>Perspectives, views and editors </b>
A window contains one or more perspectives. A perspective consists of views (e.g. Navigator) 
and editors for working with your resources.

The shortcut bar at the far left of the window allows you to open new perspectives and move
between perspectives that are already open. The perspective you are currently working with 
is shown in the title of the window and in the shortcut bar as a pushed-in icon.</item>

<item><b>Configuring your perspectives</b>
You can move views and editors around the workbench by dragging their titlebars. You can
also add more views to your current perspective by using Window > Show View. 
To reset the perspective to its original state, choose <action pluginId="org.eclipse.ui"  class="org.eclipse.ui.internal.ResetPerspectiveAction">Window > Reset Perspective</action>. 

Once you have arranged your perspective, you can save it using Window > Save Perspective As.... 
You can customize the views, perspectives and New menu operations that show up for 
your perspective. To do this choose <action pluginId="org.eclipse.ui"  class="org.eclipse.ui.internal.EditActionSetsAction">Window > Customize Perspective...</action> .  A view can
additionally be converted into a Fast View by dragging it to the shortcut bar (at the 
far left of the window). </item> 

<item><b>Join a CVS team</b>
To join a CVS development team, open the <action pluginId="org.eclipse.team.cvs.ui" class="org.eclipse.team.internal.ccvs.ui.actions.ShowCVSPerspectiveAction">CVS Repository Exploring perspective</action>. Next, specify
the location of your CVS repository. To do this, choose <action pluginId="org.eclipse.team.cvs.ui" class="org.eclipse.team.internal.ccvs.ui.repo.NewCVSRepositoryAction">New > Repository Location...</action> from the
CVS Repositories view popup menu. When the location wizard opens, fill in the details of your
CVS repository and click Finish. 

A repository location will appear in the CVS Repositories view. Expand the location, then expand
the HEAD branch. You will see a list of the modules in that repository. Select a module and choose 
<b>Checkout as Project</b> from the context menu. This will checkout the module from the CVS 
repository and create a project by that name in your workspace.</item>

<item><b>Running an Ant Build File</b>
To run an Ant build file, click on Run > External Tools > External Tools.... Select Ant Build as the launch
configuration type and click New. Identify the build file in the Location field and then click Run.</item>

<item><b>Learn more </b>
To learn more you can browse the <topic id="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/toc.xml">Workbench User Guide</topic>.</item>


</welcomePage>