<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<welcomePage 
	title="Eclipse Core Tools"
	format="wrap">
	<intro><p>Core Tools is a set of views and perspectives useful for people writing Eclipse plugins or just wanting to know what is going on under the covers. Roughly speaking there are three kinds of tools:</p>
</intro>

<item><b>Runtime tools</b>
<p>The runtime tools expose the internal behaviour of the Platform runtime as well as certain aspects of plugins (activation ordering, classes loaded, relation to other plugins, ...) and classes (load order, load nesting, ...).  Plugin developers can use this information to ensure that their plugins/classes are be activated/loaded as expected, and that they are nottaking more time/space than is warranted.</p></item>

<item><b>Resources tools</b>
<p>The resources tools expose the behaviour/performance of installed builders and listeners as well as the structure of the workspace, resources and resource deltas.</p></item>

<item><b>Metadata tools</b>
<p>The metadata tools enable users to investigate the metadata files used to maintain the resource model. Point these tools at a workspace and browse...
</p></item>
  
<item><b>Running Core Tools</b>
<p>After installing the Core Tools, you must enable them. The tools are enabled using Eclipse's debug options mechanism. To run Eclipse in &quot;debug&quot; mode, use the -debug command line option. If nothing else is said, Eclipse will look for the file &lt;eclipse install&gt;/.options. This is a Java properties file detailing which debug options should be enabled etc. See the Eclipse runtime documentation for more details. </p>

<p>The org.eclipse.core.tools plugin contains an example .options file which enables all options (except class load trace filters). To run Eclipse with the Core Tools, either copy this file to your &lt;eclipse install&gt; directory or identify it on the command line after -debug. For example, </p>
    eclipse -debug file:d:/.options

<p>Note that not all tools require enablement. You need only enable the debug options required by the tools you choose to use. See the tool descriptions for details.</p>

<p>If you are using PDE's runtime workbench then you can enable tracing and set the appropriate options for the target workspace. See PDE Guide -&gt; Running a plug-in -&gt; Running with tracing found in the standard Eclipse documentation set for more information.</p>

<p>Once you are running with the Core Tools installed, there are a number of new perspectives and views. These are accessed by opening a new perspective or using the Window-&gt;Show View functions in the workbench.</p>

<p>For more information see <topic href="doc/readme.html"><b>the readme</b></topic> in the org.eclipse.core.tools plug-in. 
</p>
</item>


</welcomePage>
