<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS TYPE="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<contexts>

<!-- F1 on F1 -->
   <context  id="f1Shell" >
      <description>Context-sensitive &quot;infopop&quot; help is provided for many interfaces, including views, wizards, fields, checkboxes, buttons, and menu items. To access this help, bring focus to the item by clicking it or using the tab key, and then press F1.

Some infopops include links to topics within the online help where you can find more information about the item.

This infopop opened because you pressed F1 while an infopop was already open.</description>
   </context>

<!-- Help page in preferences dialog, Default and Apply buttons -->
   <context  id="prefPage" >
      <description>This page sets advanced help configuration options, including installing documentation on a server, logging errors for trouble shooting, and configuring the internal help server. Select one of the options and press F1 for more information.

Click &lt;b&gt;Default&lt;/b&gt; to load the default product settings. Click &lt;b&gt;Apply&lt;/b&gt; to apply changes you have made without closing the dialog box.</description>
   </context>

<!-- Logging options group -->
   <context  id="loggingOptions" >
      <description>Specify the level of information reported in the help log file. The errors, warnings, and other information (depending on the level you select) are logged in the file .metadata\.plugins\org.eclipse.help.ui\.log, where .metadata is the product&apos;s working directory. If the documentation is installed remotely, there will be a log file on the server as well.</description>
   </context>
   
   <context  id="searchFilteringOpts" >
      <description>Choose a set of books to search.  Only results that are contained within those books will be displayed.</description>
   </context>

   <context  id="prefPageBrowsers" >
      <description>Allows selecting a web browser.  The selected web browser will be the default browser used to display help contents.</description>
   </context>

</contexts>
