<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS TYPE="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<contexts>

<!-- F1 on F1 -->
   <context  id="f1Shell" >
      <description>Context-sensitive &quot;infopop&quot; help is provided for many interfaces, including views, wizards, fields, checkboxes, buttons, and menu items. To access this help, bring focus to the item by clicking it or using the tab key, and then press F1.

Some infopops include links to topics within the online help where you can find more information about the item.

This infopop opened because you pressed F1 while an infopop was already open.</description>
   </context>

<!-- Preference page for help browsers -->
   <context  id="prefPageBrowsers" >
      <description>如果先前已经登录到 ClearQuest 数据库，则不必通过登录向导就可以再次登录。单击 Eclipse 按钮栏上的<b>登录</b>按钮，然后在“登录”窗口输入密码。窗口会预先填入先前会话的信息，包括供应者位置和用户名。要登录到不同的数据库，请使用“登录”按钮旁边的向下箭头选择正确的位置。如果选择“记住密码”选项，那么下一次不输入任何内容就可以登录 ClearQuest 会话。</description>
	  <topic label="Preferences Dialog" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-72.htm"/>
 	  <topic label="Preferences Dialog" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-72.htm"/>
   </context>

<!-- Path to custom browser on preference page for help browsers -->
   <context  id="prefPageCustomBrowserPath" >
      <description>When custom web browser is selected from the list, specify path to the browser program that launches the browser.  If the program is available on your system path, you may specify only the program name.

If the program does not accept URL as its last parameter, you may use %1 string to denote the position of the URL parameter in the command.</description>
      <topic label="Preferences Dialog" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-72.htm"/>
   </context>

<!-- Application server preference page -->
   <context  id="prefPageAppServer" >
      <description>These settings allow you to override the network interface address and port number that the internal <b>application server</b> will use.  Change the settings when the port it is trying to use is taken, or when your IP address has changed.

To automatically determine the interface address, leave the host field <b>blank</b>.

To use port dynamically assigned by the system, specify <b>0</b> in the port field.

Under normal circumstances, use the <b>Default</b> settings.</description>
      <topic label="Preferences Dialog" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-72.htm"/>
   </context>

</contexts>
